# Federico Martín Illane

Java Developer



# Personal details

-

Federico Martín Illane



fm.illane@gmail.com



Buenos Aires, Argentina



April 10th, 1990



Married



fedeillane.github.io



linkedin.com/in/ federico-illane

## Skills

Java	•••••
Spring	••••
Hibernate	••••
SQL	••••
SVN & Git	••••
JS, HTML & CSS	••••

# Languages

English



### **Hobbies**

- Sports Activities
- Gaming

### **Profile**

Java Developer offering 5+ years of experience in demanding environments. Focused on producing and mantaining systems for different companies. Skilled in developing creative, clean and performance-oriented code. Strong teamplayer, well-organized with good problem solving skills, enthusiastic learner and eager to meet challenges.

# Education

# Programming Technician: Computer Engineering Technology

Mar 2019 - Present

Universidad Tecnologica Nacional, Buenos Aires, Argentina

# Employment

### Semi Senior Java Developer

Apr 2019 - Present

Red Link S.A., Buenos Aires, Argentina

Development, maintenance and monitoring of front and back end functionalities to the online banking web application. Development of microservices and batch process. Some of the frameworks used are Spring MVC, Maven, Hibernate, JQuery, AJAX, JSP, JSF, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Database, etc.

### Java Developer Analist

Oct 2018 - Apr 2019

CDT Soluciones Tecnológicas, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Development and maintenance of "Service Portal" for OSDE, of one of the most important medical coverage company in the country. Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems. Some of the used frameworks and technologies were Spring, Hibernate, JSP, Struts, JS, JBoss, Oracle Database and consumption of SOAP web services.

#### **Technical Consultant**

Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

Avanxo S.A., Buenos Aires, Argentina

Development and design of APEX code for the Salesforce platform to customize the solution for the client. Create and consumption of SOAP and REST web services. Creation of lightning components with HTML, CSS, JS and JQuery. Improved all code quality via integrated tests. Developed and provided technical solutions for day-to-day operations.

### Java Software Developer

Sep 2015 - Feb 2018

Accenture, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Development, maintenance and training of Oracle Utilities Customer Care and Billing System (CC&B) for Metro Gas, one of the most important gas providers in the country. Customization, optimization and development of components like batch process and online reports automation. Training for new team members. Some of the frameworks and technologies used were Spring MVC, Hibernate, JSP, JS, HTML, CSS, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Database, JUnit Test.

### Courses

# **Spring Framework Master Class** Udemy

Present

Git & Github

Jun 2021

Udemy

# Java Web Services & REST API with Spring Boot

Feb 2021

Udemy